Clement Fung

Email: <u>clement.y.fung@gmail.com</u> Website: <u>https://clementfung.github.io/</u>

SUMMARY

My current research interests include the security and privacy of distributed systems. Most notably, I am interested in distributed multi-party machine learning and corresponding attacks and defenses on these system. Lately, I am especially interested in the security and privacy issues surrounding Google's federated learning.

PUBLICATIONS

Non-refereed submissions

• Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. *Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning*. arXiv Pre-print August 2018.

In Submission

- Muhammad Shayan, Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. Biscotti: A Ledger for Private and Secure Peer-to-Peer Machine Learning. In submission to NSDI 2019.
- Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. *Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning*. In submission to EuroS&P 2019.
- Clement Fung, Jamie Koerner, Stewart Grant, Ivan Beschastnikh.

 Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting.

 In submission to PETS 2019.

EDUCATION

MSc, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC MSc Supervisor: Ivan Beschastnikh. Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Thesis:

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting

Achievements:

- UBC CS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant Award, 2017
- UBC CS Department Student Service Award, 2017

Research Projects:

- Biscotti: A secure, private blockchain-based system for multi-party machine learning
- FoolsGold: A sybil-resilient federated learning protocol against model poisoning
- TorMentor: A system for distributed, collaborative, anonymous machine learning
- InsuLearn: A system for distributed learning on private medical data

• DistributedClocks: A library for vector clock instrumentation of distributed systems

Graduate Courses:

- CPSC 532R Graphical Models (*Prof. Siamak Ravanbakhsh*)
- CPSC 540 Advanced Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)
- CPSC 538W Data At Scale (*Prof. Andrew Warfield*)
- CPSC 538B Distributed Systems (*Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh*)
- CPSC 536F Algorithmic Game Theory (*Prof. Hu Fu*)
- CPSC 340 Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)

BASc, Honours, Systems Design Engineering

2011 - 2016

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Achievements:

- Sanford Fleming Award for Co-operative Proficiency Achievement in Co-op and Academics
- Graduated with Dean's Honour's Distinction 4x Dean's List
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2016
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2013 Ranked 2nd / 81 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Spring 2012 Ranked 2nd / 85 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Fall 2011 Ranked 3rd / 94 students

Awards:

- W.W. King Exchange Fellowship, Winter 2015 \$500
- President's International Experience Award, Winter 2014 \$1500
- Sanford Fleming Award, Fall 2013, Outstanding Communication in Work Term Report \$300
- Colonel Hugh Heasley Engineering Scholarship, Fall 2011 \$10000
- University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction, Fall 2011 \$2000

Research Projects:

- Driven: A system for intelligent annotation and analysis of lane changes based on dashcam videos
- FridgeMate: A mobile application and intelligent image recognition system for annotation of food in refrigerators

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Sept 2016 - Dec 2018

University of British Columbia

• CPSC 210: Software Construction

Fall 2016

Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Ryan Vogt, Jonatan Schroeder

• CPSC 210: Software Construction

Winter 2017

Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Paul Carter, Mehrdad Oveisi

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning

Fall 2017

Instructor: Mark Schmidt

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning

Winter 2018

Instructor: Michael Gelbart

• DSCI 523: Data Wrangling Instructor: Jenny Bryan, Rodolfo Lourenzutti Fall 2018

• DSCI 571: Supervised Learning

Fall 2018

Instructor: Mikchael Gelbart, Varada Kolhatkar

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern

June - August 2015

LinkedIn Corporation, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

• Analytics Team: Online Relevance Infrastructure

Software Engineering Intern

September 2014 - December 2014

LinkedIn Corporation, Mountain View, CA, USA

• Distributed Data Systems: Project Voldemort

Software Engineering Intern

January 2014 - April 2014

Voicebox Technologies, Bellevue, WA, USA

• Server and Tools team

Software Developer

May 2013 - August 2013

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research, Toronto, ON

• Software developer in Paul Boutros' bioinformatics research group

Software Developer

September 2012 - December 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON

QA Analyst

January 2012 - April 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON